FACUNDO TROITERO

• FULL STACK DEVELOPER •

mrfacundo.github.io • linkedin.com/in/facundo-t • github.com/MrFacundo
ftroitero@gmail.com • +(351) 933252437 • Lisbon, Portugal

PROFILE

I bring four years of experience in building full stack applications. I craft UIs from scratch, maintain them, leverage backend frameworks, and implement architectures. I've worked as a freelancer and participated in projects with both small teams and large organizations.

EDUCATION

42 Lisbon | Software Development

Le Wagon Berlin | Full Stack Web Development

LANGUAGES

Spanish. Native English. C1 | Portuguese and French. B2

EXPERIENCE

NIQ | JavaScript Survey Programmer

2024 - present

- Extended the survey tool (Verint) with server-side technologies (Node.js, Python)
- Developed custom JavaScript solutions to enhance interactivity and user experience.
- Used CSS libraries like Bootstrap and Tailwind for faster development and design consistency.
- Used **GitHub** and **VSCode** to develop and maintain a library of functions, standardizing code.
- · Managed project tasks in Jira, ensuring clear tracking of progress and deadlines.

E-borealis | Front End Web Developer

2022 - 2024

- Migrated high traffic websites from a CMS to a PHP framework (Codeigniter).
- Built controllers, models, and views, and integrated them with PostgreSQL, Redis and RESTful APIs.
- Developed and maintained the front end using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and libraries.
- Used **Docker** for containerization of the development environment of both front and back ends.
- Collaborated in an Agile environment, contributing to sprint planning and team coordination.
- Applied **SEO** strategies on the front end to enhance rankings.

Freelancer | Full Stack Web Developer — UI Design

2020 - present

- Developed full stack apps with **Django** and **Ruby on Rails**.
- Built dynamic front end applications with React.
- Created lightweight, easily maintainable static sites using Jekyll.
- Managed version control with Git and GitHub to track changes and collaborate efficiently.
- Managed deployment using CI/CD tools like GitHub Actions, and cloud platforms like Heroku.
- · Made architecture decisions, selecting the right technologies and frameworks for each project.

FEATURED SKILLS 🕸

Object-Oriented Programming in C++
Data Structures & Algorithms
Imperative programming in C
Concurrent & network programming
Systems administration

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

A non-blocking **Nginx** like HTTP server written in **C++** Several **C++** programs focusing on general **OOP** principles and their applications

A command line interface program similar to **Bash** featuring basic shell functionalities

PERSONAL SKILLS 🞡